

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

20, Pangyoyeok-ro 241-gil, Bundang-gu, Seongnam, Rep. of Korea

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | Sep51011@gmail.com | Assortware.github.io | Sep51011@gmail.com | Soo-hwan

"Human-Machine Interaction Technology Researcher"

About Me

Current AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and natural language processing. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github page (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

AI RESEARCH ENGINEER

INTERNSHIP

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

Major B.E. in Electronic & Communication Engineering / Minor B.E. in Data Science

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021 (Expected)

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.70 / 4.5
- Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

Research & Develop Speech and Natural Language Processing fields

Nov. 2020 - Present

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Develop Natural Language Processing toolkit used to conduct various NLP tasks (e.g. ASR, NMT, TTS, ..., etc.)
- Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

• Research & Develop English, Korean and Chinese Automatic Speech Recognition models

• Development of Multilingual Speech Synthesis Model with Support for 10 Languages

Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)

Mapo, Seoul

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models
- Research Real-time Automatic Speech Recognition Based on Kaldi Toolkit

Research Interests

Undergraduate Researcher

Speech Speech Recognition, Speech Synthesis, Voice Activity Detection, Speech Enhancement

NLP Machine Translation, Language Model, Cross-lingual

Software Software Architecture, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure, Algorithm

Skills

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Fairseq, PyTorch Lightning, Tensorflow, Keras

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

Publication

2021 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, ELSEVIER SIMPAC

2020 End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

December 9, 2020 Soohwan Kim · Résumé

Project Experience

Multilingual Speech Synthesis

REPRESENTATIVE

Kakao Brain

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Representative

• Development of a speech synthesis model that supports 10 languages

• Supports for Voice-Cloning and Code-Switching

English, Korean and Chinese ASR Models Development

Kakao Brain

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

• Development of English, Korean and Chinese Wav2vec 2.0 Models

- Experiment for improving the speed of inference
- · Comparative experiment on accuracy / inference speed by output-unit such as Character, Grapheme and Subword

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

AUTHOR

• Currently, over 100 people are stargazer this project [link]

Write Technical Reports in arXiv [link]

Extracurricular Activity

NLP Paper Reading

Kakao Brain

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Present

- Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Naver Blog

WRITER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
- Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link]

Speech Recognition Study Group

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

• Study speech signal processing (Spectrogram, Mel-Scale, MFCC etc..)

• Reading a paper of speech recognition and recording its contents [link]

Teaching Experience

Samsung Al Expert Course - Speech Recognition

Spoken Language Lab

TEACHING ASSISTANT

GROUP MEMBER

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

· Conducted Teaching Assistant role in the Speech Recognition session

Object-Oriented Programming Practice

Kwangwoon University

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- Covered basic JAVA programming, Ran laboratories and had office hours every week.
- Answered students' questions in person and marked assignments

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

| 2020 11 | 1ct Place Poople's Chaice Award | . Kwangwoon Engineering Festival (President's Award) | |
|---------|-----------------------------------|---|--|
| ZUZU.11 | ist Place. Peoble's Ciloice Award | . NWaliewooli elielileelile restival (Flesidelit S Awald) | |

2019.10 **Finalist (12th Place),** Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

| 2020.03 | School Representative | 5G-based ICT Convergence | e Service Idea Contest |
|---------|------------------------------|--------------------------|------------------------|
|---------|------------------------------|--------------------------|------------------------|

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University